# Abhishek Hegde

## Software Engineer

' Abhishek has a very articulative nature. He often looks for different ways to solve a problem and his enthusiasm for Machine Learning is amazing. If he doesn't get something he keeps on trying, looking for other resorts till he himself finds at peace with the subject matter. He has extensive knowledge of Data Science and hunger to strive further hard to improve.

> -Saurav Kumar (Senior Analyst at Accenture)

' I would rank him in first five, among the top students, I have taught in the past five years in respect of his programming ability and research skills.Overall, Abhishek is an avid-learner and highly dedicated towards his academics and his career as a whole. He has good analytical skills and is always excited to work with new technologies. His overall intelligence is also reflected in his grades for the course, which were by far one of the best in the class. I believe Abhishek would definitely be an asset to whichever organization he would work for. '

> -Dr. Vani Priya (Associate Professor at Sir MVIT)

' Abhishek is very passionate about Business Analytics, I have had the privilege of working with him on several data science projects. He is very hardworking and knows how to use data to solve business problems. He is someone I would always love to have on my team. '

> -Chaithanya Kumar A (Data Scientist Intern at Stylumia)

#### Skills

## **Data Science**

Python, EDA, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, SQL, Tableau, Problem Solving.

#### Web Development

HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, SharePoint

### **Problem Solving**

5 Star Gold Level Coder at HackerRank C++ / Python

#### Certifications

Business Analytics Nanodegree, Udacity School of Al

Deep Learning Nanodegree, Udacity School of Al

Data Scientist Track, DataCamp

Machine Learning A-Z, Udemy

#### About

A highly ambitious IT graduate, skilled in data science and software development, possessing a unique mix of business and technical experience.

## **Professional Experience**

Micro Focus, Software Engineer Aug 2020 - present | Bengaluru

Autoliv India, Web Development Intern (SharePoint) Jan 2020 - Feb 2020 | Bengaluru

- Worked on several WebApp Development projects in SharePoint (2016).
- Built Client Side Object Model (CSOM) web-parts for a subsite tool within the company's intranet site.

#### Stack used:

 dHTML- JavaScript & jQuery+AJAX, and SharePoint Customs List at backend.

#### Education

IIIT-B, PG Diploma in Data Science May 2020 – present | Bengaluru

Sir MVIT, BE in Information Sciecne & Engineering 2016 - 2020 | Bengaluru | 8.53 CGPA

## **Projects**

Dog Breed Classification using CNNs and Transfer Learning in Pytorch, Deep Learning Nanodegree Given an Image of a dog the algorithm will identify an estimate of the canine's breed. If supplied an image of a human, the code will identify the resembling dog breed

**Autonomous Driving Simulator,** *BE Capstone Project* Built a self-driving AI using CNN and image processing using OpenCV, tested on the open source Udacity Nano-programme Simulator to autonomously detect the appropriate steering angle, torque and braking based on dashboard cam input images.

## Tableau Project: YouTube US View Trends,

Business Analytics Nanodegree Built a dashboard containing view trends on YouTube from 2006-2018, visualized by category, titles, geography and channel, altogether filterable by a common Year Filter. Created from a dataset of over 22K videos.

## Generation of faces using GANs,

Deep Learning Nanodegree

This project is all about defining and training a DCGAN on a dataset of faces. The goal of the project is to get a generator network to generate new images of faces that look as realistic as possible.